{"tossups": [{"question": "The city of Ravenna hid one of these things, belonging to Dante, behind a false wall when Florentine agents tried to steal it. One of these objects was smuggled to Venice in a crate of rotting pork and cabbages from Alexandria. In an 897 synod, Pope Stephen VI put one of these objects, belonging to Pope Formosus, on trial. Another of these objects, belonging to Vladimir Lenin, remains on display in Moscow in his mausoleum. For the point, name these things, which are usually placed in graves.", "answer": "dead<b> bodies</b> (accept<b> cadavers</b> and other obvious equivalents)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A member of this Native American tribe, Stand Watie, led an attack on the supply ship<em> J.R. Williams</em>. Major Ridge was part of a triumvirate of leaders of this tribe and was among the signatories of the Treaty of New Echota, which provided for this tribe\u2019s westward migration. A syllabary for this tribe\u2019s language was developed by Sequoyah. For the point, name this one of the \u201cFive Civilized Tribes\u201d that settled in the Oklahoma Territory after being forced westward in the Trail of Tears.", "answer": "<b> Cherokee</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man served as the personal herbarium curator and physician for George Clifford III, a director of the Dutch East India Company. This scientist flipped the Celsius scale so that 0 is freezing and 100 is boiling, and he divided humans into four geographical categories, including Europaeus and Afer. This scientist wrote<em> Philosophia Botanica</em> while working at Uppsala University, and his<em> Systema Naturae</em> introduced binomial nomenclature. For the point, name this Swedish scientist who developed modern taxonomy.", "answer": "Carl<b> Linnaeus</b>", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Other Social Science"}, {}, {}, {"question": "In January 2016, this action failed to occur for the 7th time in history, due to a failure to identify Little Rock, Arkansas. In 2016, a prize for this action was donated to the Cancer Research Institute after Cindy Stowell did it 6 times while suffering from Stage 4 cancer; sadly, Stowell passed away before her performances of this action aired on syndicated TV. A 2003 rule change allows one to perform this action more than five times in a row, a change that greatly benefited Ken Jennings. For the point, name this action, a triumph on a game show hosted by Alex Trebek.", "answer": "<b> win</b>ning on<b> Jeopardy!</b> (accept descriptions thereof; do not accept or prompt on \u201cplaying on Jeopardy\u201d or other non-winning descriptions)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "This artist attributed his sense of rhythm while painting to his teacher, Thomas Hart Benton. Hans Namuth photographed this reclusive artist painting in his style of gesturalism, which was shared by his rival Willem de Kooning. This artist occasionally used shards of glass to texture his paintings, most of which are numbered. For the point, name this American painter of<em> Lavender Mist</em> and<em> Autumn Rhythm</em>, nicknamed \u201cthe Dripper\u201d for his splattered action paintings.", "answer": "Jackson<b> Pollock</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "This city was the western terminus of the Khorasan Road and was situated just north of Ctesiphon. This city, the site of the Translation Movement, was founded by al-Mansur after his brother\u2019s victory at the Battle of Zab. Harun al-Rashid constructed the House of Wisdom in this city, which was brutally sacked by Hulagu Khan as the Tigris ran black with ink and red with blood. For the point, name this center of Islamic learning and culture, the capital of both the Abbasid Caliphate and modern Iraq.", "answer": "<b> Baghdad</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "The \u201cK1C2\u201d strategy was employed by this Presidential candidate during his first election campaign, after which he stepped down as President of Columbia University. This man\u2019s Cabinet was informally dubbed \u201ceight millionaires and a plumber.\u201d This man\u2019s eventual running mate saved his own political career with the \u201cCheckers\u201d speech. This first Supreme Commander of NATO ran with Richard Nixon in 1952 using the slogan \u201cWe like Ike.\u201d For the point, name this Allied general during World War II who succeeded Harry Truman as President.", "answer": "Dwight D.<b> Eisenhower</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "The first federally funded housing initiative in this city created the community of First Houses, and this city pioneered the use of \u201cDumbbell\u201d housing. The George Bellows painting<em> Cliff Dwellers</em> depicts tenement dwellers in this city\u2019s Lower East Side, and an 1890 book of muckraking photojournalism by Jacob Riis exposed conditions in this city\u2019s tenements.<em> How the Other Half Lives</em> described conditions in, for the point, which city that processed immigrants at Ellis Island?", "answer": "<b> New York</b> City (or<b> NY</b>C)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The second epistle to Timothy identifies this figure\u2019s enemies as Jannes and Jambres. This man once asked for his name to be blotted out from the Book of Life. His older sister was struck with leprosy for criticizing this man\u2019s wife, whom he first met after rescuing her from some heckling shepherds at a well. At Meribah, this man displeased God by striking a rock in anger. For the point, name this author of the Torah who led the Israelites out of Egypt.", "answer": "<b> Moses</b> (or<b> Moshe</b>)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "During a rebellion against this ruler, a gale prevented Henry Stafford from importing troops from Brittany. This ruler allegedly ordered James Tyrell to murder Edward V and Richard of Shrewsbury, the\u201cprinces in the tower.\u201d In 2012, the body of this king was found in a Leicester parking space. The betrayal of the Stanley family led to this king\u2019s defeat to Henry VII at the Battle of Bosworth Field, marking the beginning of the Tudor dynasty. For the point, name this final king of the house of York.", "answer": "<b> Richard III</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man advised Auda ibu Tayi during the Battle of Aqaba and led guerrilla attacks on the Hejaz Railway. This man described his experiences, including his victory at the Battle of Tafileh that earned him a Distinguished Cross, in<em> Seven Pillars of Wisdom</em>. This man\u2019s promises of an Arab homeland were violated by the Sykes-Picot Treaty. For the point, name this British soldier who fought the Ottoman Empire in the Middle East during World War I.", "answer": "Thomas Edward<b> Lawrence</b> (or<b> Lawrence</b> of Arabia)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This man was the primary early backer of the failed Simplified Spelling Board project. A partner of this man, Henry Clay Frick, formed the South Fork Fishing and Hunting Club in Johnstown, Pennsylvania. This man temporarily became the richest American after selling his company to J.P. Morgan in 1901. The Homestead strike was directed against his Pennsylvania plant. For the point, name this Scotsman, the author of the essay \u201cThe Gospel of Wealth\u201d and namesake of a powerful American steel company.", "answer": "Andrew<b> Carnegie</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This organization created a trust-building program with its former rivals called Partnership for Peace. It initiated the stay-behind Operation Gladio to prepare for an armed resistance. This organization\u2019s mutual defense principle, Article 5, has only been invoked once, immediately following the 9/11 attacks. The Able Archer exercise nearly caused a war between the Warsaw Pact and, for the point, what alliance, founded in 1949 to fight communism in Western Europe, that includes the U.S.?", "answer": "<b> NATO</b> (or the<b> North Atlantic Treaty Organization</b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {}, {"question": "A non-presidential resident of this state named Harry Truman died when he refused to evacuate his home during a natural disaster. Pioneer Square in this state was the site of riots on Mardi Gras in 2001, just two years after riots on N30, or November 30th, rocked this state during a meeting of the World Trade Organization. For the 1962 World\u2019s Fair, the largest city in this state constructed the Space Needle. For the point, name this state, the location of the Mount St. Helens eruption and the Battle in Seattle.", "answer": "<b> Washington</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}